<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "JBoss_Documentation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="at-Authoring_Tools">
  <title>Authoring Tools</title>
  <para>While you can write XML using a basic text editor, the easiest way to author XML is by using an XML Authoring Tool.  A good XML Authoring Tool can auto-complete structure for you, and most importantly, validate the XML content you have written to ensure it is well-formed and valid to the standard.</para>
  <para>The number of XML authoring tools available can seem daunting to a first-time content author.  The following applications will help you to get started with XML authoring, and ease your transition into the  world of structured authoring.</para>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="section-Syntext_Serna.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="section-Oxygen_XML_Editor.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="section-XML_Copy_Editor.xml"/>
  <section>
    <title>Project Documentation Editor</title>
    <para>You may need your community to contribute directly to documentation without the upskill time required to learn DocBook XML to the required level. Or you may need to seek heavy collaboration on a document your team is writing. In these cases,  DocBook XML may not be the best choice for your project.</para>
    <para>The JBoss Community team offers an online documentation editor called <ulink url="https://docs.jboss.org/author/dashboard.action">Project Documentation Editor</ulink> that allows individual contributors and  teams to quickly contribute community documentation using a web-based  interface and clearly defined wiki markup. </para>
    <para>The wiki markup you use in Confluence is governed by the <ulink url="https://docs.jboss.org/author/display/AUTHGUIDE/Introduction">Confluence Authoring Guide</ulink>. Follow the  Confluence Authoring Guide closely to ensure you are writing wiki documentation that will be exported cleanly from the system.</para>
    <para>The Confluence Authoring Guide references the JBoss Documentation Guide  when you export your documentation to DocBook XML,  and publish the exported XML to PDF or HTML formats.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
