<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "JBoss_Documentation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="sgawin-Structure_Guidlines_Admonitions_Warning_Important_Note">
  <title>Admonitions (Warning, Important, Note)</title>
  <para>To alert readers to information that might otherwise be overlooked, DocBook v4.5 supports a number of
     admonitions you  can use to highlight concepts for readers.   The supported options are limited to:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Warning</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Important</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Note</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>The options are listed in order of priority, and alert the reader to the following conditions:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warning</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Warnings contain information that must not be ignored.  Ignoring recommendations in Warnings may result in data loss, or other catastrophic issues.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Important</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Includes information that might be easily overlooked and may cause unnecessary frustration when using the software.   For example, configuration changes that only apply to the current session, or services that need restarting before an update will apply.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Note</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Contains information that may be useful to the reader.  Ignoring a note should have no negative consequences for the reader, but may result in the reader missing out on usability tips, or a shortcut that may help them complete a task.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The way these elements are formatted depends on what publishing system you use to produce a user guide.  The
     <application>Publican</application> JBoss brand  formats this information using  lots of color, bold graphics, and
     a slightly different typeface to the normal content.   The <application>Publican</application> jboss-community
     brand and the default <application>jDocBook</application> style format the information slightly less aggressively
     by using softer colors, however  each admonition is still  quite conspicuous to the reader.</para>
  <para>When writing information for any of these elements, you can maximize the effectiveness of the information by
     keeping the structure of the information consistent.  Consider the following examples to see how effective this
     is.</para>
  <para>If using the &lt;title&gt; element, it is mandatory to start the title with the admonition level, as shown in
     the examples.</para>
  <example>
    <title>Warning and Important</title>
    <para>Use the following XML structure when creating a Warning or Important admonition.  See the sample Warning and
       Important in this example as a reference.</para>
    <programlisting language="XML" role="XML">&lt;warning&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;<replaceable>Warning</replaceable> - Warning Summary&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;para&gt;Imperative instruction to the user.  Reason why the user should obey the instruction.&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/warning&gt;</programlisting>
    <programlisting language="XML" role="XML">&lt;important&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;<replaceable>Important</replaceable> - Important Summary&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;para&gt;Information that will save the reader unnecessary frustration.&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/important&gt;</programlisting>
  </example>
  <warning>
     <title>Warning - Warning Summary</title>
     <para>Imperative instruction to the user. Reason why the user should obey the instruction.</para>
  </warning>
  <important>
     <title>Important - Important Summary</title>
     <para>Information that will save the reader unnecessary frustration</para>
  </important>
  <para>
     The following are examples of a warning and an important admonition using this structure.
  </para>
  <warning>
    <title>Warning - Open Office Package Dependencies</title>
    <para>Do not uninstall <application>Open Office</application> from Gnome Desktop systems. <application>Open
          Office</application> package dependencies may result in critical system files, including X Windows System
       files, being unintentionally  removed.</para>
  </warning>
  <important>
    <title>Important - Install MSS for JBoss 0.7 or Later</title>
    <para>Only MSS for JBoss v0.7 bundles the Diameter JBoss Service (the Diameter SAR, or Servlet Archive), which is
       required to run the Diameter Event-Charging Service.</para>
  </important>
</section>
